<entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1204.5852v1</id>
    <updated>2012-04-26T07:44:18Z</updated>
    <published>2012-04-26T07:44:18Z</published>
    <title>Context-sensitive Spelling Correction Using Google Web 1T 5-Gram Information</title>
    <summary>In computing, spell checking is the process of detecting and sometimes
        providing spelling suggestions for incorrectly spelled words in a text.
        Basically, a spell checker is a computer program that uses a dictionary of
        words to perform spell checking. The bigger the dictionary is, the higher is
        the error detection rate. The fact that spell checkers are based on regular
        dictionaries, they suffer from data sparseness problem as they cannot capture
        large vocabulary of words including proper names, domain-specific terms,
        technical jargons, special acronyms, and terminologies. As a result, they
        exhibit low error detection rate and often fail to catch major errors in the
        text. This paper proposes a new context-sensitive spelling correction method
        for detecting and correcting non-word and real-word errors in digital text
        documents. The approach hinges around data statistics from Google Web 1T 5-gram
        data set which consists of a big volume of n-gram word sequences, extracted
        from the World Wide Web. Fundamentally, the proposed method comprises an error
        detector that detects misspellings, a candidate spellings generator based on a
        character 2-gram model that generates correction suggestions, and an error
        corrector that performs contextual error correction. Experiments conducted on a
        set of text documents from different domains and containing misspellings,
        showed an outstanding spelling error correction rate and a drastic reduction of
        both non-word and real-word errors. In a further study, the proposed algorithm
        is to be parallelized so as to lower the computational cost of the error
        detection and correction processes.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Youssef Bassil</name>
    </author>
    <author>
        <name>Mohammad Alwani</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:doi xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10.5539/cis.v5n3p37</arxiv:doi>
    <link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.5539/cis.v5n3p37" rel="related" />
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">LACSC - Lebanese Association for Computational Sciences -
        http://www.lacsc.org</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:journal_ref xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Computer and Information Science, Vol. 5, No. 3, May 2012</arxiv:journal_ref>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1204.5852v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1204.5852v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
</entry>